A Guide to the Central Virginia Gay and Lesbian Publications Collection, ca. 1990-2005
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
Central Virginia Gay and Lesbian Publications Collection, ca. 1990-2005
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M334
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Publications principally were gifts of Steve Murden, Richmond, Virginia. He donated the items periodically over the course of several years in the 1990's and 2000's.
Scope and Content
This collection principally contains publications related to and concerning the gay and lesbian community in Central Virginia. Consists of organization newsletters, advertisement broadsides and flyers, newspapers, and magazines. Principally contains publications produced by specific organizations (i. e. newsletters and advertisements) and nationally and locally published magazines and newspapers that concern gay and lesbian issues but that are not associated with any one organization (i. e. The Advocate and the Virginia GayZette).
Arrangement
Arranged in one series: I. Organizations, which contains subseries A-H.
Contents List
- Organizations, 1977-2005 (Boxes 1-5)
  Alphabetical
  - Metropolitan Community Church 1994-2005, 0.38 linear feet (Boxes 1-2)
    Alphabetical with folder contents arranged chronologically.
    - Bulletins, July-December 1999 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bulletins, January-July 2000 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence to members, September-December 1999 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Holy Matrimony and Holy Union pamphlet, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - MCC Today pamphlet, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous publications, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Not-a-Dinner fundraising brochure, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Open Arms Ministry brochure, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Praxis newsletters, August-December 1999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Praxis newsletters, March-August 2000 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Seekers membership informational packet, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Welcome brochure, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - What Does It Mean To Be a Member of MCC? brochure, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Why Inclusive Language brochure, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Weekly Web newsletters, March 2000 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Weekly Web newsletters, April 2000 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Weekly Web newsletters, May 2000 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Weekly Web newsletters, June 2000 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Weekly Web newsletters, July 2000 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Weekly Web newsletters, August 2000 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Weekly Web newsletters, September 2000 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Weekly Web newsletters, October 2000 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Weekly Web newsletters, November 2000 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Weekly Web newsletters, December 2000 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Weekly Web newsletters, January 2001 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Weekly Web newsletters, February 2001 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Weekly Web newsletters, March 2001 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Weekly Web newsletters, April 2001 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Weekly Web newsletters, May 2001 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Richmond Lesbian and Gay Pride Coalition, 0.34 linear feet (Box 2)
    - Festival program, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Festival program, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Festival program, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Festival program, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Festival program, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Festival program, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Festival program, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Festival program, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Festival program, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Festival program, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Festival program, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Festival program, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Information Express Newsletters, April 1993- November 1995 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Masquerade Ball Invitation, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Pride Festival, 1992-2003 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Richmond Pride Notes Newsletters, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Silver Triangle Awards Nomination Form, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - "Tell me a Story," a dedication of Quilt Panels, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Richmond Lesbian Feminists, 0.36 linear feet (Box 3)
    - Flyer, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Flyer, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Flyer, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Flyer, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Flyer, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Flyer, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Flyer, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Flyer, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Flyer, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Flyer, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Flyerette, 2000, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Promotional Flyer, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - ROSMY, 1993-2004, 0.18 linear feet (Box 4)
    - Annual Report, 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1999-2004 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Dinner and Auction Programs, 1993-1998 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Dinner and Auction Programs, 2001-2003 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Invitations, 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Pamphlet, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Newsletters 2002-2004 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Newsletters, 1999-2001 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Newsletters, 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Newsletters, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Newsletters, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Richmond Triangle Players, 1994-2004, 0.18 linear feet (Box 4)
    - Advertisings/Mailings, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Clippings, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Fundraising Letter, 2001-2003 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Playergram Newsletters, 1995-2004 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Programs, 1994-2002 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Season Programs, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Season Programs, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Season Programs, 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Season Programs, 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Season Programs, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Season Programs, 2001-2002 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Season Programs, 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Season Programs, 2003-2004 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Virginia Partisans, 1993-2004, 0.09 linear feet (Box 5)
    - Correspondence with members, 2000-2004 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Fundraising invitations, 2000-2004 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Membership packet, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Organizational election ballots, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Political endorsement letter, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Partisan newsletter, 1999-2002 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Partisans Post newsletter, 2002-2003 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Partisans Update newsletters, 1993-1996 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Virginia Partisans Update newsletters, 1997-1999 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Virginians for Justice, 1990-2004, 0.27 linear feet (Box 5)
    - Board of Director's candidate list, 2002-2003 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - By-laws, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Casino Night and Casino Cruises booklets, 2001-2002 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Commonwealth Dinner programs, 2004-2005 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 2003-2004 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Equality Begins at Home newsletter, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Equality Virginia News newsletters, 2003-2004 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - General Assembly Voter Guide and Legislative Summary, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Guide to the 1995 Virginia General Assembly, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Invitations, 1995, 2002-2004 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Legislative Summaries and Candidate Score Cards, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Letters to members, 1995-2001 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Lobby guide, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Lobby guide, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Network '98 brochure, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Network '99 brochure, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - News newsletter, June 1989-March 1990 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - The Voice newsletter, 1990-January 1993 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - The Voice newsletter, February 1993-December 1994 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - The Voice newsletter, January 1995-December 1996 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - The Voice newsletter, January 1997-April 1998 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - The Voice newsletter, May 1998-August 1999 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - The Voice newsletter, July 1999-October 2001 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Other Organizations - A-L, 1988-2004, 0.36 linear feet (Box 6)
    - The Advocate, August 1999- August 2000 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - AIDS Memorial Quilt, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 1a)
    - American Red Cross: Good Neighbor Award pamphlet, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Artists for Life, May 20 & 21-1988 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - CARE Virginia: newsletter, Fall 1989 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - The Casablanca Gazette, Fall 1994-Summer 1995 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Central Virginia Business and Professional Guild, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Community Pages, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Curve Magazine, July 1999-February 2000 (Box 6, Folder 7a)
    - DIFFA: Heart Strings - The National Tour, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - DIFFA and The NAMES Project Foundation: An Event in 3 Acts, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Dignity/Integrity Richmond, December 1998 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Diversity Thrift, July 2004 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Gay Financial Network, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Girlfriends Magazine, August 1999-May 2000 (Box 6, Folder 12a)
    - Gotcha Covered Condom Shop - Live Wire article "Little Shop of Rubbers", 1992 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Human Rights Campaign: quarterly magazine, Summer 1999 - Winter 1999 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Human Rights Campaign: Senator Chuck Robb record on gay and lesbian issues, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Human Rights Campaign: voter score card, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - In-Touch, May 2000 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Other Organizations - L-Z, 1991-2002, 0.36 linear feet (Box 7-8)
    Consists of publications for organizations beginning with N through Z.
    - LAMBDA directory, 1998-2000 (Box 7)
    - National Lesbian and Gay Quarterly, Spring 1988-Fall 1990 (Box 7)
    - Other Voices, 1994-1995 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Out and About in Virginia, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Out/Look, Winter 1991-Spring 1992 (Box 7)
    - Phoenix Rising, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Richmond AIDS Ministry: "Lead By Their Light", 1991 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Richmond Area Nude Guys (R.A.N.G.), 2002 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Richmond for Life '91, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Richmond Gay Community Foundation, Inc: correspondence, Nov 21, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Richmond Gay Community Foundation, Inc., email, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Richmond Men's Chorus, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Richmond Virginia Gay and Lesbian Alliance (R.V.G.L.A.), n.d. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - ROBIN: The Richmond Bisexual Network, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Tidewater Bears (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Virginia Gay, Lesbian, and Bisexual Community Center (V.G.L.B.C.C.), 1994 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Washington D.C. AIDS Ride, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Women in Motion Vacations, 1999-2000 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Zen Catz, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 16)